Estelle Ishigo papers, 1941-1957
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Ishigo papers., 1941-1957.; 8.5 linear ft.
  - Biographical Materials and Internment Camp Correspondence., .5 linear ft.
    - Correspondence exchanged between Estelle Ishigo and Alan Eaton, Russel Sage Foundation, on the compilation of Beauty Behind Barbed Wire., 1945-1948.; (39 items) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 2, 1945.; Item no. 2; (3 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter from Allen Eaton, Director of the Russell Sage Foundation, Dept. of Arts and Social Work, commissioning Estelle to help in photographing artists and their work in Heart Mountain.
      - Draft letter, to Mr. Eaton., Date Created: October 5, 1945.; Item no. 3; (3 p.; 21 x 13 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Draft of a letter addressed to Mr. Eaton, Director of the Dept. of Arts & Social Work, Russell Sage Foundation, regarding watercolors being sent to Mr. Eaton and photographing Heart Mountain arts.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 8, 1945.; Item no. 5; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 14, 1945.; Item no. 6; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 15, 1945.; Item no. 7; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 22, 1945.; Item no. 8; (3 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Enclosed is a letter to M.M. Tozier, Chief, Reports Division, War Relocation Authority, describing Estelle's sketches of Heart Mountain.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 22, 1945.; Item no. 9; (5 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 24, 1945.; Item no. 10; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter requesting a rough list of Estelle's watercolor studies depicting life in Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 26, 1945.; Item no. 11; (3 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter from Allen Eaton, Director of the Dept. of Arts and Social Work, Russell Sage Foundation, regarding commissioning photographs of artworks created in Heart Mountain Relocation Center. He also addresses Estelle's concern about finding work and relocating from Heart Mountain.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 27, 1945.; Item no. 12; (5 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter regarding photographing Estelle's artworks. Enclosed is a letter addressed to Guy Roberson, Project Director, War Relocation Authority.
      - Telegram, to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 27, 1945.; Item no. 13; (1 p.; 15 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Telegram giving Estelle permission to use a photographer from Cody, Wyo. to photograph her artwork.
      - Telegram, to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo., Date Created: October 28, 1945.; Item no. 14; (1 p.; 15 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 29, 1945.; Item no. 15; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Copy of a letter addressed to Mr. Vaughn Mechau, Reports Officer, War Relocation Authority, regarding photographing artists' works in Heart Mountain.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: October 29, 1945.; Item no. 16; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter regarding photographing artists in Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: November 2, 1945.; Item no. 17; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter regarding photographing arts at Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: November 3, 1945.; Item no. 18; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Receipts., Date Created: November 7, 1945.; Item no. 20; (2 receipts; 19 x 10 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Telegram, to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: November 3, 1945.; Item no. 21; (1 p.; 15 x 21 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: November 6, 1945.; Item no. 22; (4 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter re. helping Estelle with relocating plans after leaving Heart Mountain. Also re. photographing artwork.
        Enclosed is a letter addressed to Harold D. Sturm, Cody, Wyo., regarding photographing artwork.
      - Draft letter, to Mr. Eaton., Date Created: November 10, 1945.; Item no. 23; (1 p.; 20 x 13 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Draft of a letter regarding photographing her art.
      - Letter, Cody, Wyo. to Estelle Ishigo, Hollywood, Calif., Date Created: November 23, 1945.; Item no. 24; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter regarding negatives of photos taken of Estelle Ishigo's art work.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Hollywood, Calif., Date Created: February 18, 1946.; Item no. 25; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter regarding photographing Estelle's artwork.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Hollywood, Calif., Date Created: April 26, 1946.; Item no. 26; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter written on Allen Eaton's behalf notifying Estelle Ishigo that he had some of her artworks in his possession.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Hollywood, Calif., Date Created: November 4, 1946.; Item no. 27; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter regarding interest in purchasing one of Estelle's paintings.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mr. Seido Ogawa., Date Created: July 31, 1947.; Item no. 28; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter regarding Allen Eaton's retirement from the Russell Sage Foundation. Letter co-addressed to Estelle Ishigo.
      - Draft letter, to Mr. Eaton., Date Created: April 10, 1948.; Item no. 29; (2 p.; 26 x 16 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Draft of a letter written by Estelle Ishigo updating Allen Eaton on her life since leaving Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Lomita, Calif., Date Created: April 17, 1948.; Item no. 30; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, New York, N.Y. to Mrs. Ishigo., Date Created: June 10, 1948.; Item no. 31; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
      - Letter, Cheyenne, Wyo. to Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: November 9, 1944.; Item no. 32; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter in response to Estelle Ishigo's letter requesting information regarding rules and regulations on the care and protection of animals in Wyoming. It was Estelle's intent to create a humane society in Heart Mountain.
      - Letter, New York to Miss Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mt., Wyoming., Date Created: December 6, 1944.; Item no. 33; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 77, Folder 6)
        Letter responding to Estelle's request for educational films about dogs. Enclosed is a brochure from the AKC.
  - Documents, Records and Other Materials., (.5 linear ft.)
    re Estelle's life in the Heart Mountain Relocation Camp and Federal Public Housing Authority resettlement trailer camps in Southern California.
    - A few mementos of Estelle's internment at the Pomona Assembly Center., June-July 1942.; (8 items) (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Documents, records and mementos relating to her internment in the Heart Mountain Relocation Camp., 1942-1945.; (approximately 40 items) (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - The Ishigos' property records during their internment and related correspondence., 1942-1945.; (7 items) (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Night School, Heart Mountain Adult Education Bulletin no. 1., October 24, 1942.; (7pp. Mimeographed, 1 item) (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Estelle Ishigo's pencil drawings and sketches, Heart Mountain Relocation Camp., ca. 1942- ca. 1945.; (34 pieces) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - The men had no bathtub so they made one., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 1; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 21 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Title from caption below drawing.
      - No bathtubs for men so they made one., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 2; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 23 x 30 cm.); (Edges mounted on paper.} (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - The men had no bath tub so the[y] made one., 1942.; Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 3; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 21 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Young boy., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 4; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 19 x 16 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - One has to go., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 5; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 17 x 16 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Drawing of a man leading a boy by the hand.
      - Evacuees behind fence., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 6; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 10 x 14 cm.); (Ink drawing; (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - No privacy for women and children., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 7; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 13 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Drawing of women and children in bath-house
      - We are Americans, again?., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 8; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 17 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Title from caption below drawing
        Sketch of a Japanese-American man
      - Are we Americans again?., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 9; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 24 x 18 cm.); (Mounted on paper) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - After supper a show in the mess hall., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 10; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 21 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Women's latrine., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 11; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 16 x 25 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Interior study, Heart Mountain., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 12; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 16 x 25 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Sketch of the interior of a room in Heart Mtn. Relocation Center
      - Gathering coal., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 13; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 21 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Children flying kites., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 14; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 25 x 27 cm.); (Mounted on posterboard); (Cream colored matte around drawing. (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Canteen., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 15; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 27 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - The radio said the war has ended: V.J. Day at Heart Mt. Wyoming., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 16; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 21 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Women sweeping., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 17; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 27 cm.); (Unmounted); (No caption) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Sketch of women sweeping outside barracks
      - We were given a pass and allowed to go shopping at Cody, Wyoming., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 18; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 28 x 22 cm.); (Unmounted); (No caption) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Inside of barrack., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 19; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 21 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Rough sketch of the interior of a barrack
      - Block meeting., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 20; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 16 x 24 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Title from caption above drawing
      - No privacy for men., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 21; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 13 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Sketch of men in bathhouse
      - Summer in the shade., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 22; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 15 x 24 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Sketch of Japanese Americans sitting in the shade outside of barracks
      - Interior study, Heart Mountain., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 23; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 21 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Rough pencil sketch of the interior of a barrack at Heart Mountain Relocation Center
      - Man, woman and child embracing., Date Created: September 1942.; Item no. 24; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 22 x 28 cm.); (Signed and dated); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Waiting for breakfast, Japanese camp, Pomona, California., Date Created: May 20, 1942.; Item no. 25; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 22 x 28 cm.); (Signed and dated); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Japanese American child., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 26; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 15 x 22 cm.); (No caption; (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Sketch of a Japanese American child sitting in the middle of a road in a Japanese American relocation center
      - Nowhere to go., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 27; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 15 x 22 cm.); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Sketch of Japanese American girls sitting in front of barracks
      - Outdoors at Japanese American relocation center., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 28; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 28 x 22 cm.); (Signed); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Main Street, Japanese Assembly Center, Pomona, Calif., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 29; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 22 x 28 cm.); (Signed); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - A gang of boys., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 30; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 22 x 28 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Japanese American children outside., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 31; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 26 cm.); (No caption); (Unmounted) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Sketch of children outside picking through garbage [?]
      - Play grounds., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 32; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 8 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 5)
        Title from caption on side of drawing
        Sketch of kids playing in a playground
      - Men working., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 33; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 8 x 13 cm.); (Line drawing); (Unmounted); (No caption) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Only the whispering wind., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 34; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 27 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Only the whispering wind., Date Created: December 1945.; Item no. 35; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 27 cm.); (Signed and dated) (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Photographs and snapshots taken at the Heart Mountain Relocation Camp., 1942-1945.; (57 pieces) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Michiko Iseri dance class and Heart Mountain mandolin band., Date Created: 1944.; Item no. 1; (1 photograph: black and white; 21 x 26 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Title taken from handwritten caption below photograph.
      - Estelle Ishigo, portrait., Date Created: 1945.; Item no. 2; (1 photograph: black and white; 21 x 26 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Pomona Center News staff portrait., Date Created: 1942.; Item no. 3; (1 photograph: black and white; 21 x 26 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photo of a group of people, including Estelle Ishigo, sitting for a portrait. Man in center is holding a placard that reads "Pomona Center News".
      - Baseball game., Date Created: October 24, 1944.; Item no. 4; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 12 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Snapshot of a baseball game held at Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - Estelle Ishigo and dog, portrait., Date Created: October 24, 1944.; Item no. 5; (1 photograph: black and white; 21 x 26 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Snapshot of Estelle Ishigo standing with her dog outside at Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
        Date stamped on verso - "Brown Photo Service, Minneapolis, Minn.".
      - Japanese calligraphy on split log., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 6; (1 photograph: black and white; 13 x 18 cm.); (Photograph of artwork) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Wood sculpture with flowers., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 7; (1 photograph: black and white; 18 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of a wood sculpture with artificial flowers
      - Packing to leave, Arthur Ishigo., Date Created: September 1945.; Item no. 8; (1 photograph: black and white; 11 x 8 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photo of Arthur Ishigo and dog outside of barrack at Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - Packing to leave, Estelle Ishigo., Date Created: September 1945.; Item no. 9; (1 photograph: black and white; 8 x 11 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of Estelle Ishigo and dog outside of barrack at Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - Japanese American boy., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 10; (1 photograph: black and white; 9 x 6 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Snapshot of a young Japanese American boy in overalls.
      - Rev. Nyogen Senzaki, portrait., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 11; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 6 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Handwritten on verso: "Rev. Nyogene Senzaki."
      - By the mess hall, Heart Mountain., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 12; (1 photograph: black and white; 12 x 8 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of a Japanese American boy standing outside at Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - By the mess hall, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 13; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 12 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Japanese American boy sitting with puppy., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 14; (1 photograph: black and white; 9 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Marlene and Bobby, Feb. 1943., Date Created: February 1943.; Item no. 15; (1 photograph: black and white; 9 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Portrait of two Japanese American children standing.
      - Bobby, 1943., Date Created: 1943.; Item no. 16; (1 photograph: black and white; 9 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of a Japanese boy standing inside of a barrack.
      - Geo Hirahara, Heart Mt., Wyoming., Date Created: November 9, 1945.; Item no. 17; (1 photograph: black and white; 13 x 18 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Japanese American cook and boy., Date Created: October 24, 1944.; Item no. 18; (1 photograph: black and white; 12 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Snapshot of a cook standing with a young boy. The cook is holding a fish.
      - Japanese American cook and boy., Date Created: October 24, 1944.; Item no. 19; (1 photograph: black and white; 12 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Woman and child with handmade sandals., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 20; (1 photograph: black and white; 18 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of a Japanese American woman and boy with handmade sandals.
      - Heart Mountain family., n.d.; Item no. 21; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 12 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Heart Mountain family., Date Created: October 24, 1944.; Item no. 22; (1 photograph: black and white; 12 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Snapshot of a Japanese American family.
      - Japanese American children in snow., n.d.; Item no. 23; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 12 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Snapshot of two Japanese American children standing in a lot at Heart Mountain Relocation Center. One is holding a snowball.
      - Two Japanese American men on a boat., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 24; (1 photograph: black and white; 11 x 16 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of two Japanese American men on a boat in the water.
      - Buddhist shrine., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 25; (1 photograph: black and white; 18 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of a handcrafted wooden shrine.
      - Wood shrine with flowers., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 26; (1 photograph: black and white; 16 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of a carved ornamental shrine with artificial flowers.
      - Japanese Americans working outside barracks., Date Created: October 11, 1944.; Item no. 27; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 12 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Pomona Center News staff portrait., Date Created: 1942.; Item no. 28; (1 photograph: black and white; 10 x 14 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Dog with litter of puppies., Date Created: October 11, 1944.; Item no. 29; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 12 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of dog with litter of puppies.
      - Japanese American woman standing outside., Date Created: October 24, 1944.; Item no. 30; (1 photograph: black and white; 12 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Estelle Ishigo and her dog at Heart Mountain., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 31; (1 photograph: black and white; 7 x 7 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Snapshot of Estelle Ishigo standing with her dog in front of barracks at Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - Group portrait., n.d.; Item no. 32; (1 photograph: black and white; 13 x 18 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Group portrait with Estelle Ishigo.
      - Heart Mountain High School Band., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 33; (1 photograph: black and white; 13 x 18 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Group portrait with instruments.
      - Heart Mountain B14-27 Mess Hall., Date Created: July 29, 1943.; Item no. 35; (1 photograph: black and white; 12 x 18 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Group portrait. Title written on bottom of print.
      - Art Student League, Heart Mountain, Wyoming., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 36; (1 photograph: black and white; 8 x 8 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Japanese calligraphy on wood sculptures., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 37; (1 photograph: black and white; 18 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of two wood sculptures with Japanese calligraphy painted on them.
      - Wooden inlay tray., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 38; (1 photograph: black and white; 18 x 13 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Photograph of a beautiful handmade wood tray.
      - Heart Mountain mandolin band, summer 1945., Date Created: 1945.; Item no. 39; (1 photograph: black and white; 12 x 18 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Heart Mountain mandolin band members., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 40; (1 photograph: black and white; 8 x 9 cm.) (Box 78, Folder 6)
        Portrait of band sitting on steps.